{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Segmental chips are formed during machining", "opta": "mild steel", "optb": "cast iron", "optc": "high speed steel", "optd": "high carbon steel", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cemented carbide tool tips are produced by powder metallurgy.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the diameter of the hole is subject to considerable variation, then for locating in jigs and fixtures, the pressure type of locator used is", "opta": "conical locator", "optb": "cylindrical locator", "optc": "diamond pin locator", "optd": "vee locator", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Side rake angle of a single point cutting tool is the angle", "opta": "by which the face of the tool is inclined towards back", "optb": "by which the face of the tool is inclined sideways", "optc": "between the surface of the flank immediately below the point and a plane at right angles to the centre line of the point of the tool", "optd": "between the surface of the flank immediately below the point and a line drawn from the point perpendicular to the base", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Internal gears can be made by", "opta": "hobbing", "optb": "shaping with pinion cutter", "optc": "shaping with rack cutter", "optd": "milling", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In order to prevent tool from rubbing the work __________ on tools are provided.", "opta": "rake angles", "optb": "relief angles", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The silicon carbide abrasive is chiefly used for grinding", "opta": "cemented carbide", "optb": "ceramic", "optc": "cast iron", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Drilling is an example of", "opta": "orthogonal cutting", "optb": "oblique cutting", "optc": "simple cutting", "optd": "uniform cutting", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A round nose tool may be fed eitner from left to right end or from right to left end of the lathe bed.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the cutting edge of the tool is dull, then during machining", "opta": "continuous chips are formed", "optb": "discontinuous chips are formed", "optc": "continuous chips with built-up edge are formed", "optd": "no chips are formed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A fine grained grinding wheel is used to grind hard materials.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cast iron during machining produces", "opta": "continuous chips", "optb": "discontinuous chips", "optc": "continuous chips with built-up-edge", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A single point thread cutting tool should ideally have", "opta": "zero rake angle", "optb": "positive rake angle", "optc": "negative rake angle", "optd": "point angle", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The work or surface speed for cylindrical grinding varies from", "opta": "5 to 10 m/min", "optb": "10 to 20 m/min", "optc": "20 to 30 m/min", "optd": "40 to 60 m/min", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cutting tool in a milling machine is mounted on", "opta": "spindle", "optb": "arbor", "optc": "column", "optd": "knee", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The tool made of cemented carbide wear out faster at", "opta": "slow speeds", "optb": "medium speeds", "optc": "fast speeds", "optd": "very fast speeds", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A push broach as compared to pull broach", "opta": "has less number of teeth", "optb": "is short and stocky", "optc": "removes less material for each pass of the tool", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Twist drills are made of", "opta": "high speed steel", "optb": "carbon steel", "optc": "stainless steel", "optd": "either (a) or (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A twist drill is a", "opta": "side cutting tool", "optb": "front cutting tool", "optc": "end cutting tool", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rake angle required to machine brass by high speed steel tool is", "opta": "0\u00b0", "optb": "10\u00b0", "optc": "20\u00b0", "optd": "-10\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lip angle of a single point tool is usually", "opta": "20\u00b0 to 40\u00b0", "optb": "40\u00b0 to 60\u00b0", "optc": "60\u00b0 to 80\u00b0", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The average cutting speed for turning brass with a high speed steel tool is", "opta": "15 to 19 m/min", "optb": "25 to 31 m/min", "optc": "60 to 90 m/min", "optd": "90 to 120 m/min", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum production of small and slender parts is done by", "opta": "watch maker's lathe", "optb": "sliding head stock automatic lathe", "optc": "multispindle automatic lathe", "optd": "capastan lathe", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Side rake angle on tools is provided to control chip flow.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The method of grinding used to produce a straight or tapered surface on a workpiece, is", "opta": "internal cylindrical grinding", "optb": "form grinding", "optc": "external cylindrical grinding", "optd": "surface grinding", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A fixture does not guide the tool.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Crater wear occurs mainly on the", "opta": "nose part, front relief face and side relief face of the cutting tool", "optb": "face of the cutting tool at a short distance from the cutting edge only", "optc": "cutting edge only", "optd": "front face only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gear lapping is an operation", "opta": "after heat treatment", "optb": "prior to heat treatment", "optc": "for gear reconditioning", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The facing is an operation of", "opta": "bevelling the extreme end of a workpiece", "optb": "embossing a diamond shaped pattern on the surface of a workpiece", "optc": "reducing the diameter of a workpiece over a very narrow surface", "optd": "machining the ends of a workpiece to produce a flat surface square with the axis", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A fixture is defined as a device which", "opta": "holds and locates a workpiece and guides and controls one or more cutting tools", "optb": "holds and locates a workpiece during an inspection or for a manufacturing operation", "optc": "is used to check the accuracy of workpiece", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A drill considered as a cutting tool having zero rake, is known as a", "opta": "flat drill", "optb": "straight fluted drill", "optc": "parallel shank twist drill", "optd": "tapered shank twist drill", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is wrong about ultra-sonic machining?", "opta": "It is best suited for machining hard and brittle materials.", "optb": "It cuts materials at very slow speeds.", "optc": "It removes large amount of material.", "optd": "It produces good surface finish.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In oblique cutting system, the maximum chip thickness occurs at the middle.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Larger end cutting edge angle __________ tool life.", "opta": "increases", "optb": "decreases", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lead screw of a lathe has __________ threads.", "opta": "single start", "optb": "double start", "optc": "multi-start", "optd": "any one of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A left hand tool on a lathe cuts most efficiently when it travels", "opta": "from left to right end of the lathe bed", "optb": "from right to left end of the lathe bed", "optc": "with the help of a compound slide", "optd": "across the bed", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The correct sequence of tool materials in increasing order of their ability to retain their hot hardness is", "opta": "carbide, ceramic, cermet, borazon", "optb": "ceramic, carbide, borazon, cermet", "optc": "cermet, carbide, ceramic, borazon", "optd": "borazon, ceramic, carbide, cermet", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is incorrect with reference of lathe cutting tools?", "opta": "The flank of the tool is the surface or surfaces below and adjacent to the cutting edges", "optb": "The nose is the corner, arc or chamfer joining the side cutting and the end cutting edges", "optc": "The heel is that part of the tool which is shaped to produce the cutting edges and face", "optd": "The base is that surface of the shank which bears against the support and takes tangent pressure of the cut", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the relation VTn = C, the value of n for carbide tools is", "opta": "0.1 to 0.2", "optb": "0.20 to 0.25", "optc": "0.25 to 0.40", "optd": "0.40 to 0.55", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In up milling, the thickness of chip is", "opta": "minimum at the beginning of the cut and maximum at the end of the cut", "optb": "maximum at the beginning of the cut and minimum at the end of the cut", "optc": "uniform throughout the cut", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The machining of titanium is difficult due to", "opta": "high thermal conductivity of titanium", "optb": "chemical reaction between tool and work", "optc": "low tool-chip contact area", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In orthogonal cutting system, the maximum chip thickness occurs at the middle.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lapping is an operation of", "opta": "making a cone-shaped enlargement of the end of a hole", "optb": "smoothing and squaring the surface around a hole", "optc": "sizing and finishing a small diameter hole", "optd": "producing a hole by removing metal along the circumference of a hollow cutting tool", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The different spindle speeds on a lathe form", "opta": "arithmetical progression", "optb": "geometrical progression", "optc": "harmonical progression", "optd": "any one of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the helix angle of the drill is made __________ 30\u00b0, then the torque required to drive the drill at a given feed will be more.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "less than", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The angle included between the two lips projected upon a plane parallel to the drill axis and paralled to the two cutting lips, is called helix angle.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In hot machining, tool is made of", "opta": "tungsten carbide", "optb": "brass or copper", "optc": "diamond", "optd": "stainless steel", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In ultra-sonic machining, the metal is removed by", "opta": "using abrasive slurry between the tool and work", "optb": "direct contact of tool with the work", "optc": "maintaining an electrolyte between the work and tool in a very small gap between the two", "optd": "erosion caused by rapidly recurring spark discharges between the tool and work", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The velocity of tool relative to the workpiece is known as cutting velocity.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Grinding wheels should be tested for balance", "opta": "only at the time of manufacture", "optb": "before starting the grinding operation", "optc": "at the end of grinding operation", "optd": "occasionally", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}